字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
Man, it's cold out here.
天啊，這裡好冷
How much longer must we stare at nothing?
我們要在這裡乾等到什麼時候？
We can't make money sitting here.
呆坐在這裡賺不了錢啊
The prince chickened out.
王子退縮了
We should've gone to Wessex.
我們應該去威塞克斯的
No doubt about it.
沒錯
Seriously,
真是的
we got the short end of--
我們的運氣最差…
Incoming!
又來了！
Look out!
小心！
Come on!
來吧！
Make haste and come at me!
快放馬過來啊！
You can't get to Valhalla just standing around like that!
像那樣呆站著不動 可是進不去瓦爾哈拉的！
What are you? Scarecrows?
你們是什麼？稻草人嗎？
-Damn bastard. -I can't hold back any longer.
-該死的混蛋 -我忍不住了
Does every last one of you not have the balls to fight?
你們全都這麼沒種嗎？
Ragnar!
拉古納爾！
Tolerating his attacks dishonors us as soldiers!
任憑他這樣羞辱我們 有損戰士的名譽！
We must retaliate!
我們攻擊吧！
The soldiers are ready to fight!
大家都士氣高漲！
The 4,000 of us will surely defeat Thorkell!
我們有四千人 一定能打敗托魯克爾！
Not yet.
還不行
This is Thorkell we're facing.
對手可是托魯克爾
We must be shrewd.
我們不能貿然出擊
We were tasked with the siege by His Majesty himself.
國王陛下命令我們在此圍城
Now's our chance to show our valor.
現在正是我們展現榮譽的時候
No!
不行！
When the time comes, His Highness will give the order.
時機成熟時，王子殿下就會下令出擊
For now, we bare the attack.
現在，我們得承受攻擊
Ragnar!
拉古納爾！
"Then said Jesus unto him,
“耶穌對他說
'Return thy sword to its place.
‘收刀入鞘吧
For all who take the sword
因為動刀的
shall perish with the sword.'"
必死在刀下’”
Father,
神父
I'm sorry to interrupt, but may we have some privacy?
抱歉，能請你迴避一下嗎？
Who cares about the orders of that cowardly prince?
誰在乎那個懦夫王子的命令？
We won't stay silent forever.
我們不能一直保持沉默
Come on, let's do it!
來吧，開打吧！
Yeah, that's right!
對，沒錯！
There is no need to worry.
不用擔心
Once winter comes, the order to retreat will surely come.
冬天一來，很可能就會下撤退令
We only need to be patient until then.
只要耐心等到那時候就好
Is he joking?
真是的，開什麼玩笑？
God,
主啊
please protect His Highness.
請保佑殿下
Damn it.
可惡
What a pathetic opponent.
好爛的對手
The commander is working hard.
老大還真是努力
Are they bothering you again?
又在挑釁了嗎？
Shut up, Asgeir.
閉嘴，阿斯蓋特
If they don't fight us, there is no war!
他們不攻過來，就沒有仗能打了！
You speak too loudly.
你太大聲了
And, they're being cautious.
他們很謹慎
It's because their commander is the Danish prince.
因為他們的指揮官是丹麥王子
Huh?
咦？
What?
什麼？
The prince is here?
王子來了？
Oh, didn't I tell you?
我沒告訴你嗎？
I think it's Prince Canute, second in line for the throne.
應該是丹麥王位 第二順位繼承人庫奴特王子
Mother is here.
媽媽在這裡
Ylva, too.
姊姊也在
Ari and the others are loafing while watching the sheep
亞雷和其他人又不認真放羊了
despite the big fuss about a lost sheep just the other day.
即使他們前幾天 才因為弄丟一隻羊起了騷動
Oh, that's right. It's dinner time.
對了，晚餐時間到了
I must go and tell Father!
我得去叫爸爸吃飯！
Father!
爸爸！
Tonight, we're eating meat to celebrate the Yule.
今晚我們要吃肉慶祝冬至
Oh, that's right. The winter solstice is already here.
對喔
It's so warm, that it completely slipped my mind.
最近太溫暖了，我完全忘了
This place is nice.
這裡真不錯
Plenty of pasture.
有吃不完的牧草
Moving here was the right choice.
移居來這裡是正確的決定
Ylva says it's annoying because we can't get any slaves out here
姊姊說這裡買不到奴隸 所以很不方便
even though we've never owned a slave before.
雖然我們家從沒買過奴隸
It's just like her to say that.
真像她會說的話
I like it here.
我喜歡這裡
Since we came, Mother seems to be feeling better too.
來到這裡後，媽媽的身體也變好了
Thorfinn.
托爾芬
What?
什麼事？
You are my eldest son.
你是長男
You must protect your mother and sister.
你一定要保護媽媽和姊姊
You understand?
知道嗎？
Yep.
知道了
The two of them are waiting for your return home.
她們都在等你回家
It's a very happy thing to have people like that in your life.
有人等你回家是一件很幸福的事
Do you understand?
你懂嗎？
Yeah.
懂
That's why you should give up pursuing revenge.
所以你應該放棄報仇的事
Do you think revenge would make me happy?
你覺得你為我報仇，我會開心嗎？
The village!
村子！
Father, what do we do? They're under attack!
爸爸，怎麼辦？他們被攻擊了！
Mother! Ylva!
媽媽！姊姊！
Father!
爸爸！
That wasn't… my country.
那裡不是我的國家
It was warm… with waves of grassy fields… as far as the eye could see.
氣候溫暖，牧草被風吹拂著
NOVEMBER 1013 A.D., OUTSKIRTS OF BATH
（西元1013年11月，巴斯近郊）
I wonder what's going on in our leader's head.
真不知道老大在想什麼
Winter will be here soon.
冬天就快來了
The main forces are already up north.
主力部隊早就回北邊了
Yet we're stuck here in this bleak village.
我們卻被困在這個陰鬱的村子裡
Well, at least we'll earn a few silvers before going home.
至少我們回家前可以多賺點零用錢
In that case, we should attack a bigger town.
如果要賺錢的話 我們應該攻擊更大的城鎮
Bristol is close by, isn't it?
布里斯托不就在附近嗎？
Are you a fool?
你是笨蛋嗎？
What can a mere 100 men do?
只有一百人能做什麼？
What? "Fool"?
什麼？笨蛋？
You call me an fool?
你剛剛罵我是笨蛋嗎？
Seems like only your ears aren't stupid.
看來你就只有耳朵不笨
What did you say, bastard?
混蛋，你說什麼？
What about it?
你想怎樣？
Well, after we plunder two or three more villages, we'll be done for the year.
今年頂多只能再掃蕩兩、三個村子吧
We can try again next year.
只能期待明年了
I wonder if there will be a next year.
不知道還有沒有明年
Huh?
什麼？
We've been rampaging through England for 10 years now.
我們在英格蘭征戰了十年
This year was notably cutthroat.
今年特別慘烈
Even the King of England fled the country.
就連英格蘭國王都逃到國外了
The King of Denmark has already won.
丹麥國王已經贏了
The war is over.
戰爭結束了
Really? Isn't it too early to tell?
是嗎？話說得太早了吧？
London still has Thorkell.
托魯克爾還守著倫敦
You saw how ridiculously strong that bastard is.
你也看到那個混蛋的力氣有多大了
Thorkell, huh?
托魯克爾啊？
He's certainly strong.
他確實很強
He's a Norse warrior just like all of us.
但他畢竟和我們一樣都是北方戰士
With England losing, it wouldn't be a surprise if he abandoned them now.
如果他現在放棄快完蛋的英格蘭 我也不會感到意外
-Get him, Tore! -Good lord.
-上啊，托雷！ -真是的
This again?
又來了？
Stop! Enough!
喂，別打了
What's the problem here?
到底是怎麼回事？
Ake called Tore a fool.
亞克罵托雷是笨蛋
Tore got angry.
托雷生氣了
Ake wouldn't apologize, so he insulted him back.
但亞克不道歉，所以托雷就罵回去
What did he say?
他說了什麼？
Cattle thief.
偷牛賊
He really said that?
原來他這樣回罵了
Then it can't be helped.
那就沒辦法了
Make sure to notify Askeladd of whoever dies.
不管誰死，都要跟阿謝拉特報告
What a nuisance.
真是麻煩
It's a bountiful land.
這裡很富饒
It looks like the land of my dream.
看起來很像我夢中的那塊土地
A stark contrast to Iceland.
跟冰島完全不同
The village must be buried in snow about now.
村子現在應該都積雪了
You're awake early, Thorfinn.
托爾芬，你起得真早
The sun has yet to rise.
太陽都還沒升起
Did the ruckus of the men keep you up?
那些人吵得你睡不著嗎？
Well, don't judge them too harshly.
哎呀，你就體諒一下他們
They've grown restless with all the ceaseless marching.
來到這裡之後就一直行軍 所以他們心浮氣躁
Sometimes they need to do this to unwind.
有時候需要打一場發洩一下
Don't speak to me like we're friends.
別跟我裝熟
Lately, you've been getting the wrong impression.
你最近好像搞錯了
I'm not your friend.
我不是你的朋友
You're trying to manipulate me, right?
你只是想利用我，不是嗎？
You can go on with your conceit…
你就繼續自以為是吧
until the day
直到我割斷你喉嚨的那一天為止
You're scary.
你好可怕
If that puny kid lunges at me now, then he's certainly grown up.
小不點確實長大了，竟然敢頂撞我了
Well, time is on the side of the young.
時間是站在年輕人那邊的
While you grow, I only get older.
你長大的時候，我則是變老了
The day I lose to you is coming.
我輸給你的那一天就要到了
It's only natural.
這是理所當然的事
Everyone dies, no matter their strength.
再強的人都難逃一死
Look around you, Thorfinn.
托爾芬，你看看四周
These stones weren't laid here
立在這裡的石頭
by the English of today, the Saxons.
並非現居在英格蘭的撒克遜人弄的
This was the work of the people before the Saxons.
而是在撒克遜人之前 居住在這裡的人弄的
They were a strong race.
他們是很強的民族
But 500 years ago, they were destroyed by the Saxons.
但五百年前被撒克遜人消滅
The Romans.
他們是羅馬人
The country was called Britannia.
他們將這裡稱之為不列顛尼亞
It was a sophisticated civilization.
那是個高度文明的社會
Much more than ours now.
比我們現在更文明
You're talking in circles.
別繞圈子說話了
What's your point?
重點到底是什麼？
You're impatient, aren't you?
你還真心急，是不是？
You should listen to your elders.
長輩說話要好好地聽
Well, my point is,
我的重點是
the world of mankind ages slowly but surely.
人類的世界進展雖然緩慢 但確實在衰退中
The Romans were wiped out by the Saxons,
撒克遜人消滅了羅馬人
and now the Saxons will be wiped out by us.
而我們又將消滅撒克遜人
And the glory of the Roman Empire
羅馬帝國的光榮
will fade further into the past.
將會成為遙遠的過去
Anyway, according to what the Christians say,
總之，用基督徒的話來說
the Last Judgment will befall us in 20 years.
再過20年，“最後的審判”就會降臨
It's said that when that day comes, all humans will be killed by God
據說到了那天，上帝會賜死全人類
and the world as we know it will be destroyed.
我們所知的世界會毀滅
Ragnarok.
諸神的黃昏
Look, Thorfinn.
托爾芬，你看
Isn't it ridiculous?
是不是很好笑？
It's the dawn… of the twilight age.
這是末日的黎明
There's a horse.
是馬，有一個人
An English soldier?
英格蘭士兵嗎？
No, he's friendly.
不，是友軍
That's strange.
真奇怪
We're the only ones stationed out here.
這附近應該只有我們才對
Hey!
喂！
You there! Halt!
你！站住！
We are the Askeladd army under King Sweyn!
我們是斯韋恩王麾下的阿謝拉特小隊
Where are you coming from?
你從哪裡來的？
Oh, you're part of the main force?
你們是隸屬主力部隊的啊？
I'm with Ragnar's force under His Highness Prince Canute!
我隸屬於庫奴特王子殿下 麾下的拉古納爾小隊
-I've come with a message. -Prince Canute.
-我要傳令給主力部隊… -庫奴特王子…
Are they nearby?
他們在這附近嗎？
Alas, the main force is already up north.
不幸的是，主力部隊已經北上了
They're returning to home base.
他們正在返回根據地
Then what are you doing here?
那你們在這裡做什麼？
We just stopped by a village to help ourselves.
我們只是在那個村子 停留一下，賺點錢而已
You separated of your own volition?
你們擅自離隊了？
No need to be so stiff.
不要這麼死板嘛
Your horse must be tired.
你的馬也一定累了
Why not trade for a new one?
何不換一匹新的？
Thorkell did?
托魯克爾嗎？
Yes. He's already reached that point.
對，他已經到那裡了
They are about 500 men. He's only brought his best fighters.
大約有五百人
They traced the footsteps of the main force.
他們追蹤了主力部隊的足跡
Soon, they will reach Marlborough.
很快就會抵達馬爾波羅
-Is that true? -Only 500 men to fight the main force?
喂，真的假的？
Has Thorkell lost his mind?
那個托魯克爾是不是瘋了？
And the London siege army?
包圍倫敦的部隊呢？
Prince Canute must have had 4,000 men.
庫奴特王子麾下有四千人吧
They were crushed not long ago.
他們不久前被打敗了
I'm one of the survivors.
我是倖存者之一
What's that?
怎麼了？
Thorkell led the charge coming out from the fort.
托魯克爾打頭陣，從要塞攻出來
Every one of them was as strong as a bear.
每個人都像熊一樣強大
There was nothing we could do.
根本勢不可擋
They're headed right for the main force.
他們直搗駐紮營
Your Highness!
殿下！
Lord, please let them rest in peace
主啊，請讓他們安息
-and save their souls. -Your Highness!
-願他們的靈魂… -殿下！
Thorkell is closing in!
托魯克爾攻過來了！
We must leave now!
我們得立刻離開…
I found the prince!
找到王子殿下了！
And then?
然後呢？
What happened to Prince Canute?
庫奴特王子怎麼了？
He's been captured.
他被俘虜了
He's with Thorkell's army.
在托魯克爾軍中
The surviving soldiers are concentrating their efforts on saving His Highness,
倖存的士兵正在重整旗鼓 要營救王子殿下
but we've only gathered fewer than 400 men.
但我們總共不到四百人
Morale is understandably low.
士氣也不高
I'm on my way to ask for support from the main force.
我正要去向主力部隊求援
Please join us.
請加入我們
Even 100 men would be of great help.
就算只有一百人也能幫上大忙
What do we do?
我們該怎麼辦？
You're the one who decides.
有決定權的人是你
Askeladd.
阿謝拉特
My God. This is no time to peacefully fade into the twilight.
真是的，就算末日將至 也是一刻都不得閒
Don't you hear it, Bjorn?
你沒聽到嗎，表倫？
That sound.
諸神的黃昏近了的聲音
What?
什麼？
Bury him.
埋了他
The horse he was riding too.
他騎的馬也是
You…
你…
You hear me, you bastards?
你們這些傢伙聽到沒有？
Listen well!
聽清楚了！
We are now heading out to save Prince Canute.
我們立刻出發去救庫奴特王子
We will face 500 men under Thorkell! But we will not align with other armies.
對手是托魯克爾的五百名手下
This is the moment we risk it all!
這是我們孤注一擲的時刻！
His Highness Prince Canute is second in line to the Danish throne.
庫奴特王子殿下 可是丹麥王位的第二順位繼承人
No matter which side we hand him to, there's bound to be a great reward.
不論把他交給哪一方 都能得到可觀的報酬
Can you imagine…
你們能想像嗎？
the riches that will be bestowed upon us by Denmark or England.
丹麥或英格蘭會賜給我們多少報酬
We won't let anyone steal it from under our noses.
我們不能拱手讓人
Yeah.
對
Let's do this!
好，上吧！
Victory will be ours!
勝利是我們的！
Why are you riling them up?
你煽動大家幹嘛？
It's Thorkell we're facing.
對手可是托魯克爾
-Do we even stand a chance? -Who knows?
我們有勝算嗎？
What? "Who knows?" What do you mean?
什…
It's the twilight age, Bjorn.
表倫，末日將至
If we're going out, might as well go out fighting.
如果終究都得死，那何不大鬧一場？